<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SUMU | Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></title>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/categories/sumu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-21T16:40:18+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://otb.bg/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ElSys uses SUMU for its new computer room]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2011/02/28/elsys-uses-sumu-for-its-new-computer-room/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-28T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2011/02/28/elsys-uses-sumu-for-its-new-computer-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/logo_TUES.png" alt="logo of TUES" style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer: </strong> <a href="http://elsys-bg.org">Technological School "Electronic Systems"</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry: </strong> Education</p>

<p><strong>Geography: </strong> Sofia, Bulgaria</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> cheap and efficient equipment of new computer room</p>

<p><strong>Solution: </strong> Deployment of multi-seat environment</p>

<p><strong>Software: </strong> Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 Workstation, multi-seat add-ons</p>

<p><strong>Hardware: </strong> <a href="http://ts.fujitsu.com/products/standard_servers/tower/primergy_tx100s1.html">Fujitsu TX100 S1</a> server,
<a href="http://plugable.com/products/UGA-125/">Plugable UGA-125</a> USB video, USB peripherals</p>

<p><strong>Migration: </strong> none</p>

<p><strong>Advantages: </strong> low cost, low maintenance</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>Technological School "Electronic Systems" at the Technical University - Sofia is unique in Bulgaria.
ElSys offers the best education in information technology. The school has modern computer laboratories and excellent teachers.
The school prepares specialists in the professional fields of "Automation and Electronics",
"Programming" and "Computer Networks". The school has a local Cisco Academy.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>The main challenge for ElSys was furnishing a new computer lab at minimal cost using existing peripheral hardware.
The second challenge was to use a platform that is familiar to students and which requires minimal maintenance.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Multi-seat environment SUMU was preferred because of its innovative technology, ease of use and low cost of electricity.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>Entire classroom with 15 seats was equipped with a single powerful server. As a result dramatically reduced noise pollution and heat,
electricity costs and freed up more space on each table.</p>

<p>Together we built a low voltage USB network, removing the old high-voltage AC cables which were unsafe.
The room became safer and more spacious.</p>

<p>The absence of additional computers shortens the time needed to update software, install new programs and configure settings
while leaving more time for system administrators to work on other projects in the school.</p>

<p>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 includes a variety of environments and programming languages which are used in specialized classes.
Students in the school have experience with Linux and working with the new system was not a problem for them.</p>

<p>Photos of the testing process and use of the new class room can be found at
<a href="http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.203913389618853.54571.180150925328433">http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.203913389618853.54571.180150925328433</a>
Video can be seen at <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GYbCDGTz-4">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GYbCDGTz-4</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
