<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: customers | Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></title>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/categories/customers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-01T00:06:56+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://otb.bg/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fosscourse migrates to GitHub]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2012/05/27/fosscourse-migrates-to-github/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T22:51:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2012/05/27/fosscourse-migrates-to-github</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Customer:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/fosscourse">fosscourse</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry:</strong> Open source education</p>

<p><strong>Geography:</strong> Bulgaria</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> Archive website content on a public mirror</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Import all content into GitHub wiki</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> N/A</p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> N/A</p>

<p><strong>Migration:</strong> <a href="http://mediawiki.org">MediaWiki</a> to <a href="http://github.com">GitHub</a></p>

<p><strong>Advantages:</strong> Public archive at no cost</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>fosscourse is an independent project which seeks to introduce formal open source training
into universities. It was founded and supported by <a href="http://github.com/bbatsov">Bozhidar Batsov</a>,
<a href="http://github.com/kamburov">Kiril Kamburov</a> and <a href="http://github.com/atodorov">Alexander Todorov</a>.</p>

<p>The team delivered several semesters of trainings at the Technical University - Sofia during 2008-2009
and some sporadic events at Sofia University in 2010. Since then the project has been discontinued
and its domain and web hosting have expired.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>To migrate existing content to a public archive which is free of charge and doesn't require any maintenance.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Open Technologies Bulgaria has been a backup of the project during all its years, providing technical
support and hosting when necessary. We've migrated all pages from the legacy MediaWiki into
a GitHub wiki. The migration was straight-forward with some minor issues. Unfortunately some of the original
MediaWiki pages were damaged repair and could not be migrated. We've kept a copy of the database should someone
decide to pickup and revive the project.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>Seamless migration from a legacy platform and public mirror of once active and vibrant project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BebeKarta runs on Drupal]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2012/01/04/bebekarta-runs-on-drupal/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T22:21:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2012/01/04/bebekarta-runs-on-drupal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/bebekarta.png" alt="logo of "style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer:</strong> <a href="http://bebekarta.com/">BebeKarta</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry:</strong> Internet/Community website</p>

<p><strong>Geography:</strong> Bulgaria</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> Create website for small advertisements with free/paid options</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Drupal based website, custom programming and configuration</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> <a href="http://drupal.org">Drupal</a></p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> N/A</p>

<p><strong>Migration:</strong> no</p>

<p><strong>Advantages:</strong> Flexible website</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>BebeKarta is a website for mothers to exchange or re-sell used and new kid items. It can also be
used from merchants to promote new articles to their target audience.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>To create easy to use and maintain website with free/paid subscriptions and integration into SMS
payment gateway.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Open Technologies Bulgaria was selected to develop a Drupal based website which integrates a good
amount of standard Drupal modules. During the development process we had to adjust some modules to
avoid bugs or unwanted functionality. We developed additional modules to integrate with SMS payment
gateway <a href="http://mobio.bg">Mobio</a> and allow for content expiration based on subscriptions.</p>

<p>Graphic design is made by <a href="http://www.novsait.eu">Georgi Atanasov</a>.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>Flexible website which is easy to use and doesn't require technical expertise to maintain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opencode Systems improves software testing with open source tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2011/08/22/opencode-systems-improves-software-testing-with-open-source-tools/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-22T21:50:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2011/08/22/opencode-systems-improves-software-testing-with-open-source-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/opencode.jpg" alt="logo of "style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer:</strong> <a href="http://www.opencode.com/">Opencode Systems</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry:</strong> Telecommunications</p>

<p><strong>Geography:</strong> Bulgaria/International</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> Improve existing QA infrastructure and processes</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Deploy QA lab and test automation framework, consulting, training</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> <a href="https://fedorahosted.org/beaker/">Beaker</a> automated testing framework</p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> HP blade servers</p>

<p><strong>Migration:</strong> no</p>

<p><strong>Advantages:</strong> Faster QA turnaround, better test coverage</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>Opencode Systems is a telecommunications solution provider, dedicated to open systems for the mobile network.
Opencode makes network technology that is invisible to consumers but underlies many of the mobile services they use.</p>

<p>Opencode is the industry’s number one provider of USSD Center and CAMEL Gateway which have become the operators’ choice for open network platforms.</p>

<p>Opencode SS7/SIGTRAN network centered solutions have been deployed by Tier 1 mobile operators worldwide.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>Opencode Systems\' solutions integrate specific hardware and software which runs on Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
The company wanted to improve its QA operations and deploy new test lab, complete with systems provisioning
and test automation which is native to Linux. Opencode also wanted to re-organize their development process
and follow more closely software packaging best practices for Red Hat Enterprise Linux.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Open Technologies Bulgaria was hired to evaluate the existing infrastructure and work-flows and provide
recommendations for improvements as well as implement the selected solution. After meeting with Opencode\'s
key QA and development engineers we created a report to present to higher management.</p>

<p><em>Beaker</em> test automation framework was selected because it matched all existing and future requirements of the
company and integrates very well with Red Hat Enterprise Linux. Beaker was deployed onto completely new
hardware inside the company\'s data canter and employees were trained how to use it, write automated test scripts
and how to schedule test jobs.</p>

<p>In addition Open Technologies Bulgaria helped with recommendations for hiring new QA staff.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>The new test lab allows the company to increase test coverage and provide better software to their customers.
Automation shortens test turnaround time and allows more flexibility on how and when testing is performed.</p>

<p>Improvement recommendations revealed work-flows which were not functioning smoothly. Implementing them in the long term
will provide additional benefits to Opencode.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ElSys uses SUMU for its new computer room]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2011/02/28/elsys-uses-sumu-for-its-new-computer-room/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-28T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2011/02/28/elsys-uses-sumu-for-its-new-computer-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/logo_TUES.png" alt="logo of TUES" style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer: </strong> <a href="http://elsys-bg.org">Technological School "Electronic Systems"</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry: </strong> Education</p>

<p><strong>Geography: </strong> Sofia, Bulgaria</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> cheap and efficient equipment of new computer room</p>

<p><strong>Solution: </strong> Deployment of multi-seat environment</p>

<p><strong>Software: </strong> Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 Workstation, multi-seat add-ons</p>

<p><strong>Hardware: </strong> <a href="http://ts.fujitsu.com/products/standard_servers/tower/primergy_tx100s1.html">Fujitsu TX100 S1</a> server,
<a href="http://plugable.com/products/UGA-125/">Plugable UGA-125</a> USB video, USB peripherals</p>

<p><strong>Migration: </strong> none</p>

<p><strong>Advantages: </strong> low cost, low maintenance</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>Technological School "Electronic Systems" at the Technical University - Sofia is unique in Bulgaria.
ElSys offers the best education in information technology. The school has modern computer laboratories and excellent teachers.
The school prepares specialists in the professional fields of "Automation and Electronics",
"Programming" and "Computer Networks". The school has a local Cisco Academy.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>The main challenge for ElSys was furnishing a new computer lab at minimal cost using existing peripheral hardware.
The second challenge was to use a platform that is familiar to students and which requires minimal maintenance.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Multi-seat environment SUMU was preferred because of its innovative technology, ease of use and low cost of electricity.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>Entire classroom with 15 seats was equipped with a single powerful server. As a result dramatically reduced noise pollution and heat,
electricity costs and freed up more space on each table.</p>

<p>Together we built a low voltage USB network, removing the old high-voltage AC cables which were unsafe.
The room became safer and more spacious.</p>

<p>The absence of additional computers shortens the time needed to update software, install new programs and configure settings
while leaving more time for system administrators to work on other projects in the school.</p>

<p>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 includes a variety of environments and programming languages which are used in specialized classes.
Students in the school have experience with Linux and working with the new system was not a problem for them.</p>

<p>Photos of the testing process and use of the new class room can be found at
<a href="http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.203913389618853.54571.180150925328433">http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.203913389618853.54571.180150925328433</a>
Video can be seen at <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GYbCDGTz-4">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GYbCDGTz-4</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DCH becomes Red Hat ISV partner]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2011/01/20/dch-becomes-red-hat-isv-partner/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-20T19:12:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2011/01/20/dch-becomes-red-hat-isv-partner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/dch_logo.jpg" alt="logo of "style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer:</strong> <a href="http://www.liquidity-quants.com">DCH LLC.</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry:</strong> Information Technology</p>

<p><strong>Geography:</strong> Bulgaria</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> Build IT infrastructure, present new product to market</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Build virtual machines farm and business consulting</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server 6</p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> Fujitsu <a href="http://ts.fujitsu.com/products/standard_servers/tower/primergy_tx100s2.html">Primergy TX100 S2</a></p>

<p><strong>Migration:</strong> no</p>

<p><strong>Advantages:</strong> Dynamic use of IT resources, fast product development</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>DCH LLC is a young Bulgarian company, which offers financial risk management software.
The focus of the company is to assess liquidity risk for international customers.</p>

<p>Software solutions of DCH LLC are developed on Linux and partnering with the leading open source provider - Red Hat - was an obvious next step.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>The main business challenges of the company was building a computing infrastructure that will be used for development, testing and demonstration of their software solutions
and creating partnerships in the Linux field.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Open Technologies Bulgaria was selected to implement the necessary infrastructure and provide advisory services on a partnership with Red Hat.</p>

<p>Implemented infrastructure is a farm of virtual machines. It includes instances for development and testing,
source code repository server, demonstration server, database and others. All virtual machines are installed with Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6,
which is the main platform for development of the company products.</p>

<p>DCH LLC sought our consulting services to gain a better understanding of different types of Red Hat affiliate programs and the advantages thereof.
As a result, the company chose to apply for an independent software vendor partnership.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>Implemented infrastructure of virtual machines allows the company to quickly and easily experiment with new versions and technologies
in order to offer attractive solutions to its customers. Completely virtual environment allows better use of resources and allows dynamics in their distribution,
thereby reducing the operating costs of the company.</p>

<p>DCH's partnership with Red Hat provides the company access to a stable Linux platform and guaranteed technical support.
The company can focus its resources on developing its core products rather than to continuously monitor changes in Linux distributions
and deal with compatibility problems. This avoids the waste of staff and excess labor, which is useful for the company and its customers.</p>

<p>DCH extended its market visibility, because many of the financial institutions use Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
This way, DCH offers a solution that is ready for use.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
