<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Drupal | Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></title>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/categories/drupal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-27T23:10:50+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://otb.bg/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BebeKarta runs on Drupal]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2012/01/04/bebekarta-runs-on-drupal/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T22:21:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2012/01/04/bebekarta-runs-on-drupal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/bebekarta.png" alt="logo of "style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer:</strong> <a href="http://bebekarta.com/">BebeKarta</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry:</strong> Internet/Community website</p>

<p><strong>Geography:</strong> Bulgaria</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> Create website for small advertisements with free/paid options</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Drupal based website, custom programming and configuration</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> <a href="http://drupal.org">Drupal</a></p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> N/A</p>

<p><strong>Migration:</strong> no</p>

<p><strong>Advantages:</strong> Flexible website</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>BebeKarta is a website for mothers to exchange or re-sell used and new kid items. It can also be
used from merchants to promote new articles to their target audience.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>To create easy to use and maintain website with free/paid subscriptions and integration into SMS
payment gateway.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Open Technologies Bulgaria was selected to develop a Drupal based website which integrates a good
amount of standard Drupal modules. During the development process we had to adjust some modules to
avoid bugs or unwanted functionality. We developed additional modules to integrate with SMS payment
gateway <a href="http://mobio.bg">Mobio</a> and allow for content expiration based on subscriptions.</p>

<p>Graphic design is made by <a href="http://www.novsait.eu">Georgi Atanasov</a>.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>Flexible website which is easy to use and doesn't require technical expertise to maintain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eagle Auto Transport launched its website on Drupal]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2010/08/22/eagle-auto-transport-launched-its-website-on-drupal/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-22T18:47:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2010/08/22/eagle-auto-transport-launched-its-website-on-drupal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/eagle_auto_transport_logo.png" alt="logo of Eagle Auto Transport" style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer:</strong> <a href="http://movecareasy.com">Eagle Auto Transport</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry:</strong> Transportation</p>

<p><strong>Geography:</strong> United States</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> Create a website with customized functionality</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Website built using Drupal and additional programming</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> <a href="http://drupal.org">Drupal</a>, custom modules and themes</p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> no</p>

<p><strong>Migration:</strong> no</p>

<p><strong>Advantages:</strong> modern website with a form for inquiries</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>Eagle Auto Transport is a company offering vehicles transport - cars, vans, motorcycles and more.
The company specializes in door to door shipments.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>The key business challenge for the company is building a modern web site, defining its graphic vision and the ability to process
business tailored inquiries from site visitors.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Open Technologies Bulgaria built the website <a href="http://movecareasy.com">http://movecareasy.com</a> using Drupal.
In addition, we made a custom site theme, module to automatically display images according to predefined settings,
and module for generating inquiries about transportation price.</p>

<p>Graphic design and logo are made by <a href="http://www.novsait.eu">Georgi Atanasov</a>.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>With its web site Eagle Auto Transport launched their online presence hoping to get access to more potential customers.
Specialized form to generate price inquiries allows the company to reduce the time spent talking on the phone and send a reply via email.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
