<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: QA | Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></title>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/categories/qa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://otb.bg/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-27T22:39:27+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://otb.bg/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Open Technologies Bulgaria]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opencode Systems improves software testing with open source tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://otb.bg/blog/2011/08/22/opencode-systems-improves-software-testing-with-open-source-tools/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-22T21:50:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://otb.bg/blog/2011/08/22/opencode-systems-improves-software-testing-with-open-source-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://otb.bg/images/opencode.jpg" alt="logo of "style="float: right;" /></p>

<p><strong>Customer:</strong> <a href="http://www.opencode.com/">Opencode Systems</a></p>

<p><strong>Industry:</strong> Telecommunications</p>

<p><strong>Geography:</strong> Bulgaria/International</p>

<p><strong>Business challenge:</strong> Improve existing QA infrastructure and processes</p>

<p><strong>Solution:</strong> Deploy QA lab and test automation framework, consulting, training</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> <a href="https://fedorahosted.org/beaker/">Beaker</a> automated testing framework</p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> HP blade servers</p>

<p><strong>Migration:</strong> no</p>

<p><strong>Advantages:</strong> Faster QA turnaround, better test coverage</p>

<h2>BACKGROUND</h2>

<p>Opencode Systems is a telecommunications solution provider, dedicated to open systems for the mobile network.
Opencode makes network technology that is invisible to consumers but underlies many of the mobile services they use.</p>

<p>Opencode is the industry’s number one provider of USSD Center and CAMEL Gateway which have become the operators’ choice for open network platforms.</p>

<p>Opencode SS7/SIGTRAN network centered solutions have been deployed by Tier 1 mobile operators worldwide.</p>

<h2>BUSINESS CHALLENGE</h2>

<p>Opencode Systems\' solutions integrate specific hardware and software which runs on Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
The company wanted to improve its QA operations and deploy new test lab, complete with systems provisioning
and test automation which is native to Linux. Opencode also wanted to re-organize their development process
and follow more closely software packaging best practices for Red Hat Enterprise Linux.</p>

<h2>SOLUTION</h2>

<p>Open Technologies Bulgaria was hired to evaluate the existing infrastructure and work-flows and provide
recommendations for improvements as well as implement the selected solution. After meeting with Opencode\'s
key QA and development engineers we created a report to present to higher management.</p>

<p><em>Beaker</em> test automation framework was selected because it matched all existing and future requirements of the
company and integrates very well with Red Hat Enterprise Linux. Beaker was deployed onto completely new
hardware inside the company\'s data canter and employees were trained how to use it, write automated test scripts
and how to schedule test jobs.</p>

<p>In addition Open Technologies Bulgaria helped with recommendations for hiring new QA staff.</p>

<h2>BENEFITS</h2>

<p>The new test lab allows the company to increase test coverage and provide better software to their customers.
Automation shortens test turnaround time and allows more flexibility on how and when testing is performed.</p>

<p>Improvement recommendations revealed work-flows which were not functioning smoothly. Implementing them in the long term
will provide additional benefits to Opencode.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
